All right, everybody. Today is Fed day
and Ooh, I've got some bad news I got to
talk about in this video. But first, we
got to talk about what's happening in
the market and how we expect and
anticipate a potential U-turn coming and
why. Let's break this down. So, first
things first, the market has had to deal
with a lot over the past about 6 weeks,
frankly. This is what we've called the
great suckening. Think about this.
Google raises $80 billion. SpaceX raises
$85 billion. SK Hynix in the $25 billion
ADR raise. You've got corporate
financing raises. A lot a lot of money
that includes Meta, right? A lot of
money has sort of been sucked out of
markets because companies are like,
"Hey, this is a great and frothy time to
try to raise some money. Let's do it."
And then that way we can keep
reinvesting, so to speak, in whatever
initiatives we're interested in right
now. The problem with this is yields
were also higher during that time by
about two Fed rate cuts. Now, across the
curve, we saw yields higher,
maybe 40 to 60 basis points, mostly
because of the resumption of the Iran
drama.
Ah, which has also resumed as of the
last 24 hours, which we'll talk about.
But, all of this has sort of led to an
implosion of leveraged ETFs, and you've
seen this sort of massive leverage
unwind. At the same time, you're going
into a lot of uncertainty regarding, you
know, what's Kevin Warsh going to say
today. I'll give a little bit of a
prediction on that, as well as what it
means for next week. And then, of
course, you've got Meta earnings,
Microsoft earnings, Amazon and Apple all
within the next 2 days, plus the
resumption of the Iran drama. Lot going
on. For a small note, how many of you
think this is a green screen?
>> [laughter]
>> Like, this is so cool. Look at this.
This is actually a bar on the Disney
Treasure. And this is my first time in
here. This is actually really cool. I
mean, the ship is just gorgeous. The The
only like 2 years old. And so everything
is like you can still smell the leather
the newness. It's so cool. They do, you
know, like them or not, you got to give
them credit for some of the best design.
I mean
you ever want to get design ideas
>> [laughter]
>> look around some Disney stuff. It's
incredible the attention to detail. But
anyway, uh so when we put all this
together, we've got a lot that sort of
goes into the great suckening. You know,
JP Morgan is now saying, "Oh, hedge
funds are now 50% levered and uh
leveraged ETFs have delevered by about
75%." But it's more than just the US
side. You also have to remember what's
going on in South Korea. South Korea, I
wrote this down, the KOSPI index, which
is KOSPI index, it's a PI at the end,
not a BI at the end, uh which which is
basically like their version of the S&P
500, that index literally turned into
about 50% memory stocks, mostly because
of Samsung and SK Hynix. So, imagine
memory literally being 50% of the S&P
500. That'd be crazy. Now, uh while we
look around here, I I know a lot of you
might be thinking, "Okay, but Kevin, uh
what is the S&P 500 or, you know, in
terms of memory?" Check this out. Isn't
that cool, too? Uh it's actually about 2
and 1/2% memory. So,
>> [laughter]
>> you know, when you have a massive unwind
in this basically what became this meme
stock sector, like it's not even like
the GME moment in one stock, it's
anything memory. Just
meme. Now, rightfully so, the earnings
have been fan-fricking-tastic.
But the amount of leverage that then
gets created during an unwind is pretty
painful. As that leverage unwind ends, I
actually think we we might be getting
close to a recovery in a weird way in
alignment around August 3rd when
when I'm back from vacation.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh And mostly because we seem to be
respecting, at least so far, some of the
support levels we've been talking about
in the Alpha report. Remember, we've got
an expiring coupon code on Friday for
that. And that does mean the price net
net goes up over the long term. So, if
you want to secure that best price, join
us over at mekevin.com. You can use that
coupon code cruise red. But, think about
this for a moment.
You know, when when we get through
the leverage the deleveraging, all
right? We've seen, and we get through
Apple, Meta, Facebook, and Microsoft
earnings. That's today and tomorrow. Two
big earnings days. And we get through
Kevin Warsh hawking to us, which I
really think he's going to hawk to us.
I'm going to talk about my Fed
predictions in just a moment.
And we just unfortunately get complacent
again with ideas and concepts like, "Oh,
China's selling 60-80 million dollars
worth of MANPADS." You know, the
portable air defense
rocket launchers, basically. To to Iran
to help Iran with their sovereignty, you
know, maintain their sovereignty, which
is basically a way of saying China and
Russia are kind of siding with Iran,
which we already knew. And you know, at
least we got Ukraine helping us out in
the Caspian Sea. Oh, wait. They're
actually saying, "No, it was a mistake.
We didn't actually mean to sink an
Iranian ship."
>> [laughter]
>> All right.
We'll chalk that up to a mistake.
In my opinion, that was a soft little
test to see how Iran would react.
[laughter]
But, then again, I don't want to be too
jaded here. So, let's talk about the Fed
for a moment because this is the big
deal.
I should honestly sit down. Maybe we'll
sit down one of these beautiful velvety
chairs. You know what the sound these
chairs make when you sit down on them?
Coupon expires Friday.
Coupon expires Friday. Dang.
I'll sit on a different chair.
Okay. So, my prediction for the Federal
Reserve this week is that we're going to
get a hawkish hold, mostly because uh
I think Kevin Warsh does not want to
hike, but he's going to get forced to
hike. But, I do think that he can
convince the committee, which is on the
fence,
"Give me two more data sets." The
September 16th Federal Reserve meeting
will give him two more data sets. He'll
get the July employment numbers, and
he'll also get the August employment
numbers, which are really important.
Even though ADP yesterday came in at
15K, which is still stable roughly with
last week for the weekly data, there is
a clear decay going on in the
week-over-week data, and that is bad for
the economy long term.
Some people in the comments are, "But,
Kevin, you just said you're bullish."
So, I I just have to learn when I see
these comments, I just have to be a
little bit more clear, okay? So, let's
be crystal clear.
The great suckening might come to an
end, and the deleveraging might come to
an end the beginning of September or
sorry, the beginning of August here,
August 3rd. That is short-term bullish.
Bullish for a bounce, bullish for a
recovery, bullish for some of the pain
ending mostly in hardware. Because if
you look at the S&P 500 equal weight, we
just hit new all-time highs. Like,
there's no problem there,
right? Like, if you just looked at the
S&P 500 equal weight, it's like all-time
high, all-time high, all-time high,
all-time high. Does not care.
Uh but,
the in the longer term, so I'm talking
about the next two to five years,
the labor market decaying is not
something the stock market is going to
price in in the short term. It's not
something you price in in a matter of,
you know, 1 or 2 months or even 6
months. It's something that really you
think in the back of your mind, okay,
I'm going to watch this because it's
going to prevent me from being reckless
with leverage, and then I risk getting
wiped out in the event there's some kind
of actual recession because when the
labor market rolls, it rolls fast. We
already know that this year we have more
layoffs in total than we have had last
year in technology jobs, which is really
interesting because you know, you've got
a lot of the venture capitalist going
well, technology actually creates jobs.
AI is creating jobs.
Yeah, that's going to be true in the
long term like over you know, 50 to 100
years.
In the near term, it usually destroys
jobs and the very studies some of these
venture capitalists are using like the
ramp study that I wrote down where these
venture capitalists are like, "AH, SEE
AI CREATES JOBS." I'M LIKE, "BRO,
YOU didn't read the FINE PRINT."
>> [laughter]
>> YOU'RE ACTUALLY NOT doing what you're
saying it. But, I mean that's that's
usual. Nuance gets missed. This is why I
always get frustrated when people only
rely on AI summaries as well.
Personally, I think it's a competitive
advantage for me because I don't rely on
AI summaries when I read things because
the whole point of reading or even
listening to something, you're listening
to me, is for you to think like that
mental machine in your head going, "Nah,
Kevin. I disagree with you there. You're
a freaking idiot." Or you're going, "Ah,
hmm,
>> [clears throat]
>> never thought about it that way." While
you're still a freaking idiot. "Oh,
that's actually a good point." But, that
is how you learn and every single day
your mind expands and and that that
there is a small audience of people on
YouTube, thank you, who appreciate that
kind of stuff. Uh you know, compared to
like a Mr. Beast audience, right? Uh
it's totally different segment and
that's okay. So, I enjoy doing this. I
could I would die if I had to make
YouTube content for children. My kids
are like, "Kevin." Well, they say dad.
"Daddy,
>> [laughter]
>> your videos are boring."
I'm like,
"I really enjoy them."
>> [laughter]
>> But anyway,
uh okay. So, back on the Fed. I think
we're going to get the hawkish hold. Uh
we could see an end to this forward
guidance talk. We kind of already saw an
end to that. But, keep in mind in the
last few meetings Kevin Warsh is like,
"Ah, you know, I feel comfort in the
fact that things that affect inflation
are coming down and affecting down."
Now, the opposite is happening again
because of Iran. What do we have
regarding Iran? CENTCOM yesterday told
us
that we had a surprise attack against an
airbase in Jordan. All of the missiles
or rockets were intercepted. Uh you
know, rockets are only fueled for like
the first phase of flight and missiles
are fueled through the entire phase of
flight, but they're similar. All right.
Anyway.
Um these stupid little facts. Uh anyway,
um the administration also So, the White
House is threatening to take away
soldiers' phones after images uh have
been appearing online like on X of of
Iranian strikes, which they suggest is
bad for targeting because you're kind of
letting Iran fine-tune their targeting.
And Trump is now really pissed about the
uh
uh well,
he's just he's just starting to lash
out. He says, "We're going to beat the
effing out of them. We'll be
hitting them hard. They're going to get
a beating." We already resumed some
strikes against them, and so here we are
again with this escalation, which is
something that we did call for in the
Alpha report. I said on Monday morning,
I said, "We have a lack of durability
going into this week." And this is why I
think you should be part of it. There's
really good perspective in the Alpha
report every week, but not just
short-term. It's also long-term. You
know, over the last week, I think we
bought like, you know, $200,000 worth of
stocks, and you can kind of see where
that money is going. If you want to see
it, join the Alpha report. Sent one
notification yesterday as well. But what
was very interesting is uh if you look
at
um
this uh okay, Trump has we're going to
be at I just lost my train of thought.
We're going to be um hitting them hard.
They're going to take a beating. Oh,
yeah, at the beginning of the week, I
said, "Look, we have a lack of
durability going into this week. You've
got Fed concerns, you've got earnings
concerns, and you don't actually have a
memorandum of misunderstanding. You
literally have nothing. So, you don't
even have a concept of a plan to go on.
So, the odds something goes wrong are
very, very high." And sure enough, here
we are. Surprise attack followed by,
well, now counterattacks and all the
other nonsenses. Not good. So, then we
have uh that uh we talked about the man
pads. Oh, yeah. CTAs Let me say
Commodity Trading Association traders uh
trading in uh trading in as sellers. So,
selling stocks every single scenario
next week.
I consistently inverse that.
>> [laughter]
>> You should probably, too. Consider that.
Don't take my advice for it. Not
personalized financial advice, of
course, but I think when the CTAs are
like, "Oh, yeah, we're going to be
selling in every scenario next week.
It's going to be the most green stock
forward guidance.
>> [laughter]
>> It's It's like they've I think the suits
put this out uh as just pure
manipulation. I just I I really don't
believe
>> [laughter]
>> Uh but anyway, finishing my thought on
Kevin Warsh, okay. So, here, let's look
at some decor while I finish my thoughts
on Kevin Warsh. Uh on Kevin Warsh
finishing the thoughts,
uh I really think that he is uh he's
going to hawkish hold us. Uh this is so
beautiful. Uh not only is he going to
hawkish hold, but he's going to make it
very clear that he has no idea, you
know, he's not making any projections
about the future. We're going to look at
the data over the next few months to get
a trend, and then we will make a
decision. Today, we decided not to make
a decision uh or we made a decision to
hold, basically, right?
That's my impression. I think he
actually might keep the meeting shorter
today. This is also going to be one of
the first meetings This is the bad news.
This is going to be one of the first
meetings that I actually won't be live
for, but I will do a summary video
afterwards because we've got a big uh
thing scheduled with the kids today,
which I think will be really cool. I'll
probably share a photo of what happened
after uh the Fed meeting. That'll be
really sick. Has to do with the cruise.
And no, it doesn't have to do with the
coupon code I made Kevin Derico. Uh but
um
uh that'll be really fun. So, I will be
missing the live, but I'll do a summary
video afterwards. But basically, there's
no reason for Kevin Warsh to make any
prognostications. We shouldn't expect
him to because he's already said he's
killing forward guidance. I I he's going
to say, "Look, things are going in the
wrong direction on inflation and uh the
labor market so far is still holding up
even though there are weakening signs
that we want to pay attention to as
long-term investors. Uh and bottom line,
we're not raising rates today, but there
are compelling reasons to consider that
for the next meeting, which is September
16th, which right now markets are
pricing in an 80% chance of a hike for
only about a 35-ish percent chance of a
hike today. So, I think no hike today,
but get ready September
especially with the resumption of the
Iran war.
Any reason to hold is starting to
evaporate, which isn't good. So,
let's do a couple or a few uh NOOB
VERSUS PRO BREAKDOWNS. I'm putting them
at the end of the video. I also turned
off HDR because somebody in my comments
was like, "Kevin,
stop filming in HDR. It makes the
highlights so gross."
All right.
I'm sure you don't sound like that, but
I did it for you.
>> [laughter]
>> So, we'll we'll we'll see what other can
I said, "Kevin, your color looks so bad
now."
>> [laughter]
>> Can't win. Uh anyway, uh so quick little
uh noob versus pro summaries here. Uh
people have been wondering why the stock
market has been selling off and the noob
says, "Well, you know, it's just sell in
May and go away a little bit delayed."
The pro looks at the data and says, "No,
dude. Google raised $80 billion at the
beginning of June. Kevin Warsh hawked it
to us in the beginning or mid of June.
You got Space X raising $85 billion in
the beginning of June. SK Hynix listed
their $25 billion ADR and Meta went to
the markets to raise money. When you add
up all of that money that got sucked out
of the market in just the last 8 weeks,
there should be no freaking surprise the
stock market is having trouble going to
all-time new highs on hardware. But, if
you actually look at the RSP index or
the S&P 500 equal weight, it's up.
All-time highs.
Uh I think that was a good little noob
response there.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh let's do another one.
Uh okay, how about uh
oh yeah, okay.
The noob says, "Hey, how come memory
prices are so all time high, 4X, and yet
all of a sudden memory stocks are
selling off?" SK Hynix says earnings
weren't that bad. The pro says, "You're
right, SK Hynix's earnings weren't that
bad. They were actually really good.
Even though technically they missed,
they did a phenomenal job with over 83%
margins and signed 10 long-term
contracts for high bandwidth memories uh
memory deals, which could smooth out
earnings fluctuations for them, kind of
like a defense contractor, which is good
cuz memory is usually up and down, boom
and bust, boom and bust. But, what
actually happened was the South Korean
stock market got to the point where 50%
of the entire stock market was memory,
and it was propped up by a bunch of
debt, margin, and leverage traders, and
guess what? Once leverage starts going
down, people start panic selling, and
then you get a little oopsy-doopsy
correction. Totally normal.
Okay.
Uh what else we got? By the way, yeah,
the SK Hynix numbers were fantastic. I
just want to do a quick note on the SK
Hynix numbers.
Uh they did miss on revenue technically
by 5.4%. Some analysts are indicating
that's because of a higher share of high
bandwidth memory, uh which uh tends not
to sell at spot pricing. Uh DRAM and
NAND, which are up like 4X year over
year in price, they tend to sell at spot
or close to spot, so the current market
price.
High bandwidth memory sells on a
long-term contract over years, so it
kind of gets buttered out. Uh as a
result, there can also be a little bit
of a discount to current pricing because
people think pricing will normalize.
Totally normal to expect. And SK Hynix
does a higher percentage of bandwidth
memory compared to the other
manufacturers like Micron. Worth paying
attention to as well, but again, that's
the deeper analysis that that we should
be watching.
Uh
let's do let's do one more here. Okay,
so
the noob comes in and says the war with
Iran is just the United States of versus
Iran with Israel pegging the United
States into the deeper portion so the
depths of the war. The pro says this is
way more expansive. We just had Ukraine
attack an Iranian ship in the Caspian
Sea. We have Russia enabling the
manufacturing of drones of four Iran and
we have China selling weapons including
now $60 to $80 million of Manpad
portable defense rocket launchers
to Iran. So when you kind of start
putting pieces of the puzzle together,
you go, "Wow, this is really
interesting." On one axis, you've got
the US, Israel, and Ukraine, and on the
other axis, you have Russia, China, and
Iran. That's starting to sound like
things are going more in the direction
of World War III, not not in the
direction of World War III. Yikes.
Uh okay, cool. So I think those are some
good little
snippets there.
What else did we have? Anything else for
me to add context to? Let me just
double-check the SK Hynix numbers.
Uh 83% margin is so freaking good. It is
such good margin. Oh yeah, CoStar
sinks 12% after hours. You know, CoStar
any of these like
frankly platform companies for real
estate where they're not actually buying
real estate, but they're just trying to
make money off of transactions, hard to
make money off transactions right now
cuz transaction volumes are down because
rates are high. Doesn't actually mean
prices are down. Now real estate prices
have fallen in certain areas and
markets.
Fortunately, knock on wood, not yet in
the markets that we're in. Anyway, thank
you so much for watching this video.
Remember to join us over at
meetkevin.com.
Oh, look at that. They put little
fossils in the countertop. That's really
See, that's that attention to detail I
think is really cool. Look at that. That
is awesome. That's very, very cool how
they do that. Wow. Yeah, I've not seen
that before. Inside the slab of granite
or whatever that is.
And uh
yeah, good luck out there. The
vacation's almost over, so just buckle
up.
See you soon. Bye.